<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<buildorderfile xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="buildorderxmlschema.xsd">
    <buildorderfilename>initialbuildorderfile</buildorderfilename>
    <author>andrew long</author>
    <dbversion>1</dbversion>
    <fileversion>1</fileversion>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>3 Hatchery no gas into roach</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Overlord	
14	Spawning Pool	
16	Overlord	
16	Hatchery	
16	Zerglings	Number or Zerglings depends on the amount of pressure you feel you're under. 2 is the minimum.
16	Queen	
22	Hatchery	at 3rd base location
22	Queen	as soon after the first Queen spawns as possible.
25	Overlord	
		Walk your first Queen down to your Natural after the first Inject Larva. Use the second 25 energy from the Queen to put a Creep Tumor at your Natural Expansion.
35	Overlord	
37	Overlord	
38	Queen	at 3rd base Hatchery
42	Extractor x 3	
45	Overlord	
49	Overlord	
56	Hatchery	Macro hatchery in Main Base
56	Evolution Chamber	
55	Lair	
57	Roach Warren	
61	Metabolic Boost	
61	 +1 Ground Carapace	
81	Glial Reconstitution	
		From here defend against Protoss aggression and then pick a tech path. Many Zerg have been choosing to Make a Spire and go for Mutalisks if they haven't been pressured a lot up to this point.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Speedling Expand into Baneling Openning</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Overlord	
15	Spawning Pool	
14	Extractor 	
15	Overlord	
15	Queen	
15	2 Zerglings	
20	Metabolic Boost	
20	Hatchery	
23	Queen	Start 2nd Queen as soon as first finishes. Send 1st Queen to Natural after Spawning Larva.
23	Overlord	
25	Baneling Nest	
29	Overlord	
35	Spine Crawler	at Natural Expansion
30-40 or around 6:30		At this point you should be choosing between Drones, Zerglings, and Banelings depending on what your opponent is doing.
Around 7:30ish		From here on you can add a 3rd Hatchery if you feel safe or choose a higher tech path.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>2 Base Muta/Ling/Bling</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Overlord	
15	Hatchery	
16	Extractor	
16	Spawning Pool	
17	Overlord	
		2 Queens, 4 Zerglings, and 1 Drone as the Spawning pool finishes.
24	Zergling Speed	
27	Overlord	
30	Queen	at Natural expansion for creep spreading and Hellion Defense.
31	Spine Crawler	
43	Extractor	
44	Lair	Keep Droning up as much as possible during this phase. You'll need to have enough Drones to saturate your next 3 Gas Geysers while still having enough on Minerals.
54	Extractor x 2	
60	Overlord x 3	
59	Spire	
70	Baneling Nest	
70	Evolution Chamber	Start making Zerglings during this phase in preparation for defending / attacking later.
		From this point make as many Mutalisks as possible and get upgrades. Try to Harrass safely with the Mutalisks to keep the Terran in his base and allow you to take a safe third. </buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>10 Pool Speedling Baneling</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>10	Spawning Pool	
10	Extractor x 2	Cancel one Extractor after making a Drone to be at 11/10 supply. Let the other Extractor finish for gas. 
11	Overlord	
11	Zerglings x 3	Total of 6 Zerglings (3 eggs) immediately after Overlord finishes.
		Keep making Zerglings at this point. 
15	Queen	
17	Metabolic Boost	Pull Drones off of gas after getting 100 for this upgrade.
17	Overlord	
		Harrass with Zerglings. Try to do some damage, but try to keep as many Lings alive as you can while more filter in. Making your opponent lose mining time due to defending is nearly as good as killing Drones.
21	Overlord	
		If you are pushed back it's better to pull out of the base and build up a large group of Zerglings before attacking again rather than lose your remaining Zerglings for minimum damage. Killing Queens and the Spawning Pool should be priority targets as well.
~26	Drones	Put Drones back on Gas at this point. Drone up to 13 and then continue to make Zerglings while keep 3 Drones on Gas.
26	Baneling Nest	
		Try to finish off your opponent with Zerglings and Banelings. Unless you've got a significant amount of damage already you're going to be all-in. Expanding after this point will be difficult. </buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname> Hatchery 1st 2 base ZvT</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Overlord	
15	Hatchery	send your 2nd Overlord to your Natural to watch for Bunkers, etc. Seal sends out a Drone to scout at 15 supply in this game. (Daybreak)
16	Spawning Pool	
17	Overlord	
19		Seal makes 4 Zerglings and sends 4 Drones to handle the light Bunker pressure at this point.
19	Queen x 2	
25	Extractor	
26	Overlord	
30	Queen	for creep spread. Seal uses the first energy on his Main base Queen to inject and uses the first energy on his Natural base Queen to start a creep tumor.
33	Sprine Crawler	at Natural choke point. This is optional, but never a bad investment at this point. Seal did scout a Reactor Hellion opening from his opponent as well.
33	Overlord	
35	Metabolic Boost	Seal takes 1 Drone off gas after he starts this, but it's not necessary for a newer player to worry about tiny details like this so much. Just including it to be thorough. :)
40	Evolution Chamber	at choke to help deny Hellion aggression.
41	Overlord	
44	Overlord	
48	Hatchery	Macro Hatch at main.
47	Extractor x 2	
51	Ground Carapace	
53	Extractor	
52	Baneling Nest	
55	Overlord	Seal has been making nearly all Drones at this point. Only made barely enough Zerglings to scout and stay alive. 
60	Lair	
64	Overlord	
68	Overlord	Normally you'll be making 2 Overlords at a time once you're on two bases. Not always the case, but a good general rule to follow.
70		At around this supply count Seal starts making Zerglings and Banelings in preperation for common Terran pushes.
80	Overlord	
84	Baneling Speed	
85	Spire	Seal gets aggressive out on the map with his Zerglings at this point. It's good to try to deny a third base if the Terran is trying to take one, but don't lose too many units doing it.
83	Hatchery	at third base.
85	 +1 Melee Weapons	
85	Burrow	
		At this point try to stay safe while denying their third base. Since yours is later it's very important that you keep them from taking theirs. After the Spire is up use Mutas to harrass, but focus mostly on Zerglings and Banelings. Seal adds in an Infestation Pit at about 13:50 in this game and relies on Ling/Baneling/Infestor to finish the game. Also use burrowed Banelings to catch advancing armies and draw scans out of your opponent as well.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Hatchery 1st mass Zergling double ups</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Overlord	
15	Hatchery	TLO scouts with his 14th Drone in this game.
16	Spawning Pool	
17	Overlord	
17	Extractor	
17	Queen x 2	Queens immediately after Spawning Pool finishes.
24	Overlord	You can make a few Zerglings here too if you feel the need. TLO was not pressured at all at this point and continued to Drone.
27	Queen	3rd Queen at main right after the first 2 finish. TLO uses the Queen at his natural to start a Creep Tumor instead of inject with his first energy. He also moves his main base Queen to the natural after using Inject Larva on his main Hatchery once.
32	Metabolic Boost	Pull Drones off gas for a bit at this point.
32	Spine Crawler	At Natural expansion. This is necessary with the way that TLO is playing since he hasn't made any Zerglings yet.
32	Overlord	
36	Overlord	You'll usually be making 2 Overlords at once at most times once you're on 2 bases.
39	Zerglings x 8	TLO makes his first Zerglings. He's been largely relying on his 2 Queens at the natural and a Spine Crawler to stay safe up to now.
43	Overlord	Starts making a lot of Zerglings. Up to 22 right away. These are largely defensive.
54~		TLO is trying to Drone as much as possible while at the same time making a safe amount of Zerglings.
55	Hatchery	Macro Hatch at his Natural Expansion.
55	Extractor x 2	TLO is at 37 Drones and is making largely Zerglings for now. Still making a couple Drones each cycle.
57	Overlord x 3	
58	Evolution Chamber x 2	
64	 +1 Melee Weapons	
64	 +1 Ground Carapace	
67	Hatchery	At 3rd base location.
77	Overlord x 2	
88	Lair	TLO makes his Lair at his natural expansion, but this the main is fine as well. He's making mostly Zerglings now with just a few Drones here and there.
104		at 11 minutes TLO already has almost 100 Zerglings and is sitting on approximately 50 Drones. After 1/1 finishes he becomes very aggressive and manages to deny the third base of MKP and do some damage in the natural. This style relies on great Larva Injects to keep your Zergling numbers high. TLO adds a Baneling Nest on at about 13 minutes. He gets an infestation pit, but only starts Infestors after starting 3/3 and Adrenal Glands. The key to making this work is constantly attacking the 3rd base while expanding a lot yourself. Burrow can also be added later on if need be. </buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Forge Expand 6 Gateway timing.</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Pylon	at natural to begin wall-off.
16	Forge	
16	Nexus	Start making Probes again after starting the Nexus. 
18	Pylon	
18	Gateway	
18	Cannon	Do not make the Cannon part of your wall. 
19	Assimilator x 2	
23	Cybernetics Core	
33	Warp Gate Reasearch	
33	Zealot	to block space in wall
33	Pylon	
36	 +1 Ground Weapons	
41	Pylon	
41	Gateway x 5	
44	Pylon x 4	
		Warp in 6-8 Sentries
62	Pylon	in a forward location
62	Assimilator x 2	
		Warp in a round of Zealots.
75	Pylon	another forward pylon.
		Warp in Stalkers and push
		From this point you can add a Twilight Council and get Blink and +2 Ground Weapons while expanding if your push can't kill them. The main goal of the push should be to kill the 3rd base and then do as much damage afterwards as it can while still staying safe and not overextending. </buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Nexus 1st Warp Prism into Collosus</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Pylon	at natural ramp to start wall off.
17	Nexus	
17	Pylon	
18	Gateway	
20	Forge	
21	Assimilator x 2	
23	Cannon	Behind Gateway and Forge preferably. 
23	Cybernetics Core	
28	Pylon	
30	Zealot	to fill gap in wall
32	 +1 Ground Weapons	
32	Warp Gate Research	
33	Pylon	
38	Robotics Facility	
38	Sentry	
		Make 2 Senties from the Gateway after the Zealot.
41	Pylon	
43	Assimilator	
47	Gateway x 3	
49	Warp Prism	as soon as Robotics Facility finishes. Make Observer after Warp Prism
51	Pylon x 2	
51	Assimilator	
55	Robotics Bay	
58	 +1 Ground Armor	right after +1 Weapons.
65	Pylon	
		Begin Harass with Senty drop + Zealot warp-ins. 
67	Gateway x 2	
75	Thermal Lance	
		From here continue building Colossi and Gateway units for a push near +1/+1 finishing. </buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>1 Gateway expand into Robotics + Double Forge Passive style</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Pylon	
12	Gateway	
14	Assimilator	
16	Pylon	
17	Cybernetics Core	
24	Warp Gate Research	
25	Pylon	
30	Nexus	
31	Assimilator	
31	Pylon	
39	Robotics Facility	Creator makes 2 Observers before anything else with this build, but this can be altered depending on the situation.
39	Gateway x 2	
45	Pylon	
48	Forge x 2	
51	Assimilator x 2	
54	Pylon	
60	 +1 Ground Weapons	
60	 +1 Ground Armor	
62	Twilight Council	
66	Pylon x 2	
75	Blink	
86	Robotics Bay	
88	Gateway x 3	
		Use the observers to keep an eye on troop movements. If your opponent is playing passive you can take a 3rd as you start +2/+2. Otherwise you can make units and chonoboost your Gateways to stay alive instead of your Forges. Scouting is the key to staying alive in this build!</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Nexus first into 7 Gateway push</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: The idea behind this build is to take a very early Nexus in order to power quickly to 7 Gateways for a large early attack. Attack should commence at around the 10 minute mark if all goes well.
        9	Pylon	
17	Nexus	
17	Gateway	Cut Probes for a moment to get this out.
18	Pylon	
18	Assimilator	
22	Cybernetics Core	
		Hero makes 2 Zealots before his first Stalker in this example of the build. This does keep you a bit safer from very early pokes from your opponent. 
32	Warp Gate Research	
33	Pylon	
44	Gateway x 2	
42	Pylon x 2	Keep in mind that Supply number is appoximate. Hero lost a Zealot here which is why the supply is showing 2 lower than the last step. Building orders in this guide are listed in the order they were made.
42	Assimilator x 2	
		Hero has mostly been Chrono Boosting his Probes at this point, but starts to focus more on Chrono Boosting Gateways now. 
59	Gateway x 4	Hero begins to save Chrono Boosts now to prepare for the big 7 Gate attack.
59	Pylon	
62	Pylon	Generally you want to be making 2 Pylons at once at this point to keep up with your supply.
		Hero has 9 Sentries when his 4 new Gateways finish. He also warps in a lot of Zealots after this. He has a good amount of Stalkers too, but the priority is put on having plenty of Sentries for Force Fields and Gaurdian Shield. Unit count at the time of attack is 8 Zealots, 11 Stalkers, 8 Sentries. Warp ins after the initial attack are pure Stalker/Zealot. 
        </buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>3 Gateway Blink with aggressive 3 Gate opening</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Pylon	
11	Gateway	Wait to start Chrono Boosting your Probes until after making the Gateway. Only Chrono Boost Probes once.
14	Assimilator	
15	Pylon	
15	Cybernetics Core	Cut probes for a moment if necessary to get out the Core on 15.
16	Zealot	Cut Probes again slightly to get the first Zealot Started.
20	Warp Gate Research	Chrono Boost Warp Gate Research. Start Stalker after starting this upgrade.
24	Assimilator	
24	Gateway x 2	
25	Pylon	Oz puts Probes on his second gas around now.
27	Twilight Council	
27	Pylon	Forward Pylon on preparation for aggression. 
34	Blink	Oz warps in 3 Stalkers and then starts Blink. He Chrono Boosts Blink rather than the Gateways.
36	Pylon	
		Oz tries to be aggressive with his Stalkers and 1 Zealot now.
41	Pylon	
49	Pylon	
		At this point Blink should have just finished and you can become aggressive. Watch what your opponent is doing and respond accordingly. In this game Oz ends up having to proxy two Robotics Facilities to get out an emergency observer to survive Dark Templars.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>3 Gate FE into 2 Base fast Hight Templar with Storm</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This build gives you a safe 3 Gateway expand and rushes to Psionic Storm right afterwards. It's designed to crush early mid-game Terran Bio pushes and allows you have a strong counter attack timing and a safe 3rd base.
        
        9	Pylon	
13	Gateway	
15	Assimilator	
17	Pylon	Sage uses his first 3 Chrono Boosts on Probes.
18	Cybernetics Core	Start saving Chrono Boosts now if you haven't.
19	Assimilator	
22	Warp Gate Research	Chrono Boost out a Stalker, followed by a Sentry. Scout with the Stalker. 
23	Pylon	Chrono Boost Warp Gate Research once.
27	Gateway x 2	Make a 2nd Sentry out of the first Gateway and a 3rd as well.
35	Nexus	
36	Pylon	In this example Sage uses this Pylon as a forward Pylon and tries to put a little pressure on his opponent. This is optional. Sage has a total of 6 Senties and 4 Stalkers at his opponent's base.
46	Pylon	Sage starts Chrono Boosting Probes at both bases now.
52	Assimilator x 2	
56	Twilight Council	Sage pressures a bit with his army, but doesn't all-out attack.
60	Pylon	
62	Templar Archives	
64	Pylon	
64	Gateway x 3	Sage loses a couple units here so the supply changes accordingly.
64	Pylon	
72	Psionic Storm	Sage has about 60-70 energy saved up on each Nexus at this time.
72	Pylon x 2	Sage starts warping in Templar at this time to start gaining energy for Storm on them.
74	Pylon	
82	Pylon	Sage goes up to 6 High Templar and also warps in some Zealots.
94	Pylon	
		At this point Sage kills Hack's army in mid map and pushes to win the game while taking a 3rd base behind it. A big part of what makes this so successful is how he kept his early-game Sentries and Stalkers alive. Loses as few units as possible in the early game is essential.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Forge FE into +1 Zealot push into 7 Gate +2 Blink all in. </buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>9	Pylon	
17	Forge	May have been a planning Nexus first, but Probe scouted Pool first from Zerg which may have changed his mind
18	Nexus	Chrono Boost your Probes early on.
18	Pylon	
18	Photon Cannon	
18	Gateway	Wall completed with Forge/Gateway/Pylon
20	Assimilator x 2	
25	Cybernetics Core	
36	Warp Gate Research	
36	 +1 Ground Weapons	Chrono Boost both Forge and Cybernetics Core. Tassadar has 1 Chrono Boost saved up on each Nexus at the point these two upgrades start.
36	Pylon x 2	
37	Gateway x 3	
43	Assimilator x 2	
45	Pylon	
45	Twilight Council	
45	Pylon	Tassadar has Chrono Boosted Warp Gate Research and +1 Ground Weapons 3 times each at this point and hasn't used it on anything else.
45		Tassadar warps in Zealots and tries to pressure the 3rd base now that his +1 upgrade has finished.
55	Pylon	The last 2 Pylons have been forward Pylons near the Zerg 3rd base.
56	 +2 Ground Weapons	Chrono Boost on this and Blink
56	Blink	
56	Pylon	Some units were lost in the attack at the 3rd.
56	Gateway x 3	
64	Pylon x 3	All Chrono Boosts are used on Blink and +2 at this point.
		Upgrades finish at approximately 10:45 in this example. At this time push out and use your Chrono Boosts on your Gateways as you attack. Tassadar has 6 Sentries with this attack as well that he created shortly after pressuring the 3rd base with +1 Zealots. Keeping these Sentries alive until the +2 Blink push will make it much more effective.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>1 Barracks Gasless FE into Reactored Hellion into Marine/Medivac</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This build gets you a fast 2nd base and an attack timing with Marines and Medivacs based around +1 Infantry Weapons and Stimpack. 
        
        10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks	
16	Orbital Command	
16	Command Center	at natural
17	Supply Depot	
19	Refinery x 2	
24	Bunker	at front
25	Orbital Command	
25	Factory	build next to Barracks
25	Reactor on Barracks	
30	Barracks x 2	
31	Supply Depot	
		Swap Factory and Barracks and begin Hellion production.
32	Tech Lab on Barracks after switch.	
37	Supply Depot	
40	Stim Packs	
51	Supply Depot	
54	Starport	
54	Reactor	Switch reactored Factory with a Barracks. Start new Reactor on Factory next to Starport.
54	Reactor	on 3rd Barracks
55	Engineering Bay	
64	 +1 Infantry Weapons	
64	Refinery	at Natural
70		Switch Starport on to Reactor that was just made by the Factory. Start Medivac production.
70	Supply Depot x 2	
75	Tech Lab	on Factory
		Push with Marine/Medivac as +1 Infantry Weapons and Stimpack finishes. You can also get Combat Shields directly after Stimpack and push then. </buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>1 Barracks Expand without gas into 5 Barracks Marine aggression. </buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This build allows you to get a fast 2nd base and a large group of Marines to be aggressive with early in the game. It sacrifices a tech advantage by trying to do early damage with shear numbers and Micro. 
        
        10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks	
17	Orbital Command	
17	Command Center	
18	Supply Depot	
21	Barracks x 2	
24	Barracks x 2	
25	Orbital Command	
30	Supply Depot	
38	Supply Depot	
42	Bunker	at Natural Expansion
50	Refinery x 2	Push out with your Marines at around this time and put pressure on the Protoss. Be careful not to get your army split be Force Fields.
52	Supply Depot	
55	Tech Lab x 2	on 2 Barracks
56	Refinery	
55	Engineering Bay	Supply is less because you will have theoretically lost some Marines at this point.
55	Stimpack and Combat Shields upgrades	Start Marauder production out of Barracks with Tech labs.
55	Supply Depot	
70	 +1 Infantry Weapons	
		Supply counts after your first push will vary greatly depending on how many units you use. Instead of exact supply numbers concentrate intstead on the order in which things are built at this point. Go for Medivacs or Ghosts depending on which is appropriate for the situation.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>1 Barracks Gasless FE into 3 Barracks Marine/Marauder/Medivac</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks	
16	Orbital Command	
17	Command Center	
17	Supply Depot	
19	Barracks	
21	Barracks	
23	Refinery	
24	Bunker	At Natural Expansion
26	Orbital Command	
30	Tech Lab	on one Barracks
32	Supply Depot	
39	Supply Depot	
39	Stimpack	Make only Marines at this point.
44	Refinery	
49	Supply Depot	
49	Engineering Bay	
53	Factory	
57	Refinery	
57	 +1 Infantry Weapons	Make Turrets around this time if necessary due to Cloaked Banshees
62	Supply Depot x 2	At this point Depot timings may vary depending on if you've lost units or not by now.
62	Reactor	on Barracks
62	Starport	
66	Reactor	on Factory
70	Barracks	
72	Combat Shields	Switch Starport over to the Reactor and begin Medivac production around this time.
		At this point begin looking at options to do damage with drops or pokes. You can also choose to try to take a third base at this time as well unless you plan on staying on two bases or have taken too much early damage. Generally in bio TvT you need to be active around the map and trying to expand as fast as possible.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>2 Barracks FE into Marine/Medivac</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This opening allows you to put a lot of early Bunker pressure on the Zerg without sacrificing too much in your own economy. It transitions nicely into Marine/Medvic play for an aggressive midgame.
        
        10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks x 2	Cut SCVs for a moment to build both Barracks on 12
15	Orbital Command	
15	Supply Depot	
		Put on pressure with Bunkers and Marines while making SCVs and saving for a Command Center.
21	Supply Depot	
30	Command Center	
35	Barracks x 2	
35	Supply Depot	
35	Refinery x 2	
39	Orbital Command	On second Command Center
44	Tech Lab	
46	Supply Depot	
51	Combat Shields	
58	Supply Depot	
62	Supply Depot	Put on some pressure with Marines during this phase, but be careful not to lose too many.
71	Factory	
71	Supply Depot	
76	Supply Depot	
79	Stimpack	
80	Starport	
80	Reactor on Facotry	From this point add on Reactored Medivacs and try to put more pressure on the Zerg. Consider going into drop play as you add Siege Tanks on back home and possibly take a third base.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Command Center first into 3 Barracks Marine Marauder Medivac</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>vDescription: This build gets your a good economy going early and allows you to got for some upgrades and Medivacs at the same time while building a strong Bio army. 
        
        10	Supply Depot	
14	Command Center	
15	Barracks	
16	Barracks	
19	Orbital Command x 2	Your second Orbital Command at the Natural will probably start slightly later.
22	Barracks	
26	Supply Depot	
28	Refinery x 2	
30	Supply Depot	
41	Tech Lab	
41	Supply Depot x 2	
47	Stimpack	Start Marauder when the tech lab finishes.
49	Bunker	at Natural. This is optional, but nearly always necessary. 
49	Engineering Bay	
54	Supply Depot	
		You can add a second Bunker on if you feel the need as well.
62	 +1 Infantry Weapons	
62	Supply Depot	
64	Factory	
		It's not a bad investment to put a Missile Turret at your mineral line around this time. It's optional, but useful if you get the impression that Dark Templar might be a possibility.
69	Supply Depot	
73	Refinery	
75	Tech Lab	on Barracks
75	Reactor	on Barracks
75	Reactor	on Factory (To switch onto Starport later.
75	Starport	
83	Concussive Shells	Simply start this upgrade after Stimpack
		Push when your first 2 Medivacs come out. Although Jjakji didn't research it until nearly the 11 minute mark in this game, usually Combat Shields is gotten with this build as well. From her you can add in a Ghost academy and think about taking a 3rd base as you try to harass your opponent with MMM pokes and Medivac drops.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>1 Barracks FE into fast 3rd CC into Marine/Tank/Medivac with fast upgrades for Infantry.</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: The idea behind this build is to make a fast 3rd Command Center in order to saturate your main and natural bases extremely quickly. You use this fast income to get a high Marine count early on and fast upgrades while transitioning into a more normal Marine/Tank/Medivac mid game.
        
        10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks	
15	Supply Depot	
16	Orbital Command	
19	Command Center	
23	Command Center	
25	Barracks x 2	
27	Orbital Command	
28	Refinery x 2	
34	Orbital Command	
42	Engineering Bay x 2	Make Marines at this point and use your Barracks as a wall off.
44	Supply Depot	
47	Barracks	
49	 +1 Infantry Weapons	
49	 +1 Infantry Armor	
49	Supply Depot	
49	Factory	
56	Barracks	During this time you should be active around the map with a small group of Marines. Deny Creep spread and look for hidden Expansions. Also keep and eye on the front of the Zerg base.
56	Supply Dept	
59	Tech Lab	on Barracks
64	Armory	at 50% +1/+1 completion
64	Tech Lab	on Factory
64	Starport	
65	Stimpack	
65	Refinery x 2	
70	Supply Depot	
		At this point you should have started Siege Tank production, +2/+2 for your Marines and have a Medivac on the way. Get Combat Shields on the Second Tech lab and then move out soon afterwards to try to do damage and secure a place for your 2rd Command Center to fly to.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>3 Barracks push</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This is the classic 3 Barracks Marine/Marauder Push. Jjakji does this one in a way that appears to be a Reaper Expand. The idea behind the build is to try to kill a Protoss opponent who is found playing too greedy. 
        
        10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks	
13	Refinery	
16	Orbital Command	
16	Barracks	
16	Tech Lab	on first Barracks after 1 Marine
17	Supply Depot	
19	Concussive Shells	In this instance Jjakji goes for a Reaper First to Scout with.
20	Reactor	on second Barracks as soon as it completes.
20	Barracks	Switch to marauder production after finishing the Reaper from Barracks one.
24	Supply Depot	
		Jjakji tries to build a Bunker for the Reaper but gets denied. This is optional.
29	Supply Depot	
29	Combat Shields	
35	Supply Depot	
42	Supply Depot	Making sure not to miss Supply Depots is vitally important to this build. Missing even one can greatly reduce the speed and effectiveness of the build.
		In most cases the attack hits at around the 7 minute mark in game time. Jjakji pulls 4 SCVs with his push to buffer some damage, but this is optional.
55	Supply Depot	
		Jjakji also builds two bunkers at the base to make this more effective. It divides your opponent's attention as well. Try to micro well and there will be a good chance you will have enough units to win right out if they have been playing greedy.
		</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Reactor Hellion Fast Expand into two Starport Banshee.</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This build gets you a fast expansion and tries to surprise the Zerg opponent with late Cloaked Banshees. 
        
        10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks	
13	Refinery	
15	Orbital Command	
16	Supply Depot	
17	Factory	
18	Reactor	on Barracks. Stop Marine production after 2 Marines so that you can start the Reactor on exactly 50 gas.
20	Command Center	
		Swap Factory onto the Reactor and start Hellion production.
26	Supply Depot	
27	Refinery	
34	Orbital Command	During this time Jjakji is saving for 2 Starports.
34	Starport x 2	SCV production is not cut in this build.
37	Tech Lab	on Barracks
38	Bunker	in this game Jjakji puts a Bunker in his main in order to stay safe while making the Startports/Banshees
39	Tech Lab x 2	on each Starport
39	Supply Depot	
		There is no need to expand with your Command Center until you feel safe. Just make SCVs.
44	Cloak	for Banshees. Jjakji also makes a Marauder for safety. 
47	Banshee	Start Banshee production at this point, but hide the completed ones.
51	Supply Depot	Jjakji makes nothing but SCVs and Banshee at this point.
54	Supply Depot	Keep active with Hellions around the map, killing Creep Tumors, etc.
57	Siege Tank	Start Siege Tank production now. Your should have enough to build 1 tank and 2 Banshees.
		From this point you can continue to make Banshees and get Siege mode or start to focus more on going into a normal Marine/Tank mid game while you take a 3rd base. In this game Jjakji actually kills Leenock with the Banshees.
		</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>1 Barracks with gas FE into Marine Combat Shields/Stim/+1 timing into M/T/M</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This build gets you a strong economy early on while giving you a strong Marine only force to defend and possibly do damage with. It transitions smoothly into a normal Marine/Tank/Medivac composition with two factories to allow you to catch up in the Tank count quickly if need be. 
        
        10	Supply Depot	
12	Barracks	
13	Refinery	
15	Orbital Command	
16	Supply Depot	
16	Tech Lab	Make after your first Marine.
20	Command Center	
21	Combat Shields	
25	Barracks x 2	
26	Supply Depot	
29	Orbital Command	
30	Engineering Bay	
30	Reactor x 2	
31	Stimpack	
31	Supply Depot	
33		In this instance Fin builds 3 Missile Turrets because he suspects Cloaked Banshees. This step is optional. 
42	 +1 Infantry Weapons	
49	Supply Depot	
54	Factory	at this point Fin loses some Marines to Cloaked Banshees. Supply will reflect that.
59	Supply Depot	
62	Refinery	
62	Supply Depot	
66	Reactor on Factory	
66	Starport	Fin moves out at this point to try to secure the middle of the map.
65	Barracks	
65	Factory	
		From this point poke with your Marine force. You'll have Medivacs coming soon to help with any Stims you may use. Begin Tank Production out of both factories and continue to upgrade after that to create a strong mid-game army. 
		</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>TvP Proxy double 11 Barracks into Bunker Rush  </buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This build attempts to kill the opponent early by getting Bunkers and Marines in their main base. It's especially good against players that are playing economically greedy for whatever reason. This is a risky build and must be Microed well to be successful!
        
        10	Supply Depot	
11	Barracks x 2	Hidden near the opponent's base. In this instance Thorzain starts a 12th SCV to make it appear that he's doing something relatively normal, but cancels once the scouting Probe leaves vision range. He continues making SCVs normally once the second Barracks is started.
14	Orbital Command	
16	Supply Depot	Begin making Marines, but keep them hidden if possible for now.
23	Bunker	in opponent's base. Thorzain moves out with 3 Marines and 2 SCVs to start out and rallies Marines after that.
26	Supply Depot	Thorzain brings another SCV to bring the total to 3 as he brings in more Marines. He starts with 1 Bunker and protects it while it builds.
		When your Bunker finishes use it only to protect the Marines from Zealots and Probes. Try to be actively out in the Protoss base doing damage to whatever is most important as much as possible. De-powering Gateways should be a priority. Start a second Bunker if you're able to and continue to Micro your Marines and SCVs well!
		
		</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Dark Templar Expand</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>9 Pylon
13 Gateway
14 Assimilator
16 Pylon
17 Assimilator
@100% Gateway: Cybernetics Core, Zealot.
22 Pylon
@100% Cybernetics Core: Sentry, Warpgate Research
@100% Sentry: Sentry
ASAP: Twilight Council
28 2x Gateway 
@100% Twilight Council: Dark Shrine
Pylon
Pylon
31 Sentry
34 Nexus
@100% Dark Shrine: 2x Dark Templar
</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>7 Pool vs zerg</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>6/10 Drone
7/10 Spawning Pool
6/10 Drone
7/10 Drone
8/10 Drone
100% Spawning Pool
9/10 Double Extractor trick
7/10 3 Zerglings
@ 100% Zerglings pop out, send 4-6 Drones with Zerglings
12/10 Build 2 Spine-crawlers on Opponents Creep
Continue to reinforce with Zerglings to base or build more Spine-crawlers with remaining drones</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>8 Pool vs protoss</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>The most important thing with this is to not lose your Zerglings. Protoss must pull a lot of probes to kill 6-8 Zerglings. If Protoss doesn't pull enough Probes, kill them. If he does, run around his base and try to pick off his Probes one at a time.
        
8 Spawning Pool
7 Drone
8 Drone
9 Overlord
9 Zergling
10 Zergling
11 Zergling
12 Zergling
At this point you can transition to making Drones, or continue making Zerglings for an all in attack

Scouting
The only special scouting would be if you are attempting this build on a large 4-player map. In this case, send out your 8th Drone (after Spawning Pool is started) to scout.

Execution

Based on what opening Protoss used, your attack priorities will change.

If Protoss used a Forge Fast Expansion build, your Zerglings will most likely arrive right as the Forge finishes (assuming you know where he is). If he has tried to wall himself in, attack the weakest building to open up the wall.

When Protoss opens with Forge Fast Expansion, the most common response to an 8 pool is to abandon the pylon and the Forge, and make another pylon and cannon near the mineral line, to protect the Probes. If he has the forge, but hasn't put any cannons near it, he is trying to do this. When you see this, you should run your Zerglings into the Protoss base and start trying to kill Probes. If he gets up a Photon Cannon, then at that point you can run the Zerglings back, and kill the Pylon and Forge near his Natural.

If Protoss opens with a more standard 9 Pylon 12 Gateway, try to kill the pylon powering the Gateway. For the most part, this will come down to Zergling vs. Probe micro.

The most important thing with this is to not lose your Zerglings. Protoss must pull a lot of probes to kill 6-8 Zerglings. If Protoss doesn't pull enough Probes, kill them. If he does, run around his base and try to pick off his Probes one at a time.

Most of the time you will follow up your initial 8 Zerglings with Drones and transition into a normal game but with an economic advantage if you were able to do damage with your Zerglings. In some situations, based on how much damage you do, you may want to continue making zerglings, but this is usually not recommended.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>7 roach rush</buildname>
    <race>zerg</race>
    <buildinstructions>10 Extractor trick
11 Overlord
11 Spawning Pool
10 Drone X 5
15 Extractor
14 Drone x2 (3 Drones on gas when Extractor finishes)
16 Queen (cast larva asap)
18 Overlord
18 Roach Warren (@ 35/50 Queen)
17 Overlord
17 Roach X7
31 Drone x3
34 Overlord
34 Hatchery (expand)
33 Drone X3
36 Lair
36 Extractor X3 (optional - expansion geysers @ 75/100 Hatchery)

This build is unique in that there is no scout denial or scouting. Instead the goal is to let the enemy know you are going 7 Roaches, so he is forced to defend instead of tech-ing up or expanding. And your own scouting is done when you actually attack his base, where you will clearly see what units he has. At the same time you open up a window to expand and tech up yourself.


</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>7 Gate Immortal All-In</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>Description: This 2 base all-in aims to kill the Zerg opponent's third base before they're able to tech towards Mutalisks or Infestors. It relies on 2 or 3 Immortals and a high number of Sentries that will be used to cut the opponent's army into pieces with Force Fields. Also of importance is a Warp Prism that will be used both for reinforcing your army and moving back injured units, as demonstrated by Squirtle in this game against BBoongBBoong.
        
        9 Pylon
17 Nexus
17 Forge
17 Gateway
17 Pylon
18 Photon Cannon
20 Assimilator x2
@100% Gateway: Cybernetics Core, Zealot.
@100 Gas: +1 Ground Weapons
@100% Cybernetics Core: Warpgate Research, Stalker
38 Robotics Facility
@100% Robotics Facility: Constant chrono boosted Immortal production (until 3)
Assimilator x2 
@~7:30: 3 Gateways 
@100% Warpgate Research: Gateway x3 

Stop Probe production at ~45. You want optimal saturation (16 Probes) at both mineral lines and 3 Probes in all 4 Assimilators.
As your last Immortals finishes, queue up a Warp Prism and push out immediately. Your last three Gateways should finish shortly afterwards. If you have a proxy Pylon you should start warping-in there, if you don't then warp-in one round of units at home before waiting for the Warp Prism to arrive for further warp-ins. If you don't have a proxy Pylon then you should bring a Probe to build one so that your Warp Prism can focus on protecting your Immortals.
When you push out, your army should consist of 3 Immortals, 1 Zealot, 1 Stalker and 7 Sentries.
After the Warp Prism, you should build an Observer to be on the safe side against Burrow micro.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>4 Gate Rush</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>9 Pylon
12 Gateway + Probe Scout
14 Assimilator
16 Pylon
@100% Gateway: Cybernetics Core, Zealot
@100% Zealot: 21 Stalker
@100% Cybernetics Core: Warpgate Research
@50% Warpgate Research: 3 Gateways (4 total)
@90% Warpgate Research: Proxy Pylon

After Chrono Boosting the initial Probe production twice, the rest should be spent on Warpgate research. This should be 4 Chrono Boosts in total. The final Chrono Boost will finish exactly as Warp Tech completes.
Start all 3 additional Gateways at ~50% Warpgate Research. If constantly Chrono Boosted, the Gateways and Warpgate Research should finish at the same time. They must be finished on time or it is likely your rush will fail against a competent opponent.
Although it is preferably to hide your attack, hiding a 4 Gate is usually a formality. This is as your Nexus' energy should signal to any observant opponent that you are doing a 4 Warpgate push.

PvP
In PvP, target firing Stalkers with your Stalkers is extremely important at all times because whoever retains the most Stalkers has a significant micro advantage in battle. However, using a higher number of Zealots than your opponent can be useful when trying to break up a ramp that your opponent is holding because you can force their ranged units to retreat.
If your opponent is planning on holding their ramp with Sentries, you must build your Pylon close enough to their cliff (but not right next to their cliff) that you can warp Zealots on the high ground. Don't build your Pylon close enough to the cliff that it can be easily sniped.
In PvP, your Zealot and Stalker should protect the Probe that builds the proxy Pylon, which should be built as close to the doorstep of their base as possible. Some builds, such as the 3 Stalker Rush, rely on sniping the Probe before a proxy Pylon can be build; be careful of such builds and consider sending two Probes for building Pylons if you scout your opponent using one.
It is also important to note that on some maps, such as Bel'Shir Beach and Tal'Darim Altar, the 4 Gate is the dominant strategy because it is impossible to use Force Fields to prevent units being warped into the main base.
PvZ
When using a one gas 4 Gate, prioritize Stalkers if you scouted Roaches or a heavy investment in Spine Crawlers. Prioritize Zealots to deal with high Zergling counts.
Utilising a two gas 4 Gate allows you to use more Sentries in your composition at the cost of Stalkers. The advantage of this is that it will allow you to block Zerg reinforcements by Force Fielding their main ramp; it also allows you to use Forcefields to trap Roaches against Zealots so that they cannot kite.
Aim to do significant economic damage by killing Drones, Queens or the natural expansion. Accept losses to destroy a Hatchery, a units worth in Drones, or a tech building but do not overcommit in the event that the Zerg has heavily defended their main base.
No matter which variation that you use, be careful of Zerglings sniping your pylon or counter-attacking into your main-base. It is often a good idea to fully wall-off your main base with an additional Pylon when you move out to place down proxy Pylons.
PvT
This strategy has gradually become useless vs. Terran opponents. Modern build orders all account for the possiblity of a 4 Gate with either Bunkers or proper tech-timings. However, a 4 Gate can still be used occasionally as a surprise strategy.
In general, Zealots and Stalkers will be the primary units used. However, if your opponent is relying heavily on Bunkers to defend, warping in a Sentry so that you can use a Force Field to prevent the Bunker being repaired can be useful.
If the opponent is building Marauders then try to focus them down first; this is as the Concussive Shell upgrade prevents your Stalkers from cost-effectively kiting against Marines.

</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>2 gate</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>If you wish to proxy your Gateways, then either your 7th or 8th Probe will need to be sent out to build this Pylon at a proxy location.
        
10 Pylon
10 Gateway
10 Gateway
10 Probe
11 Probe
12 Zealot
14 Zealot
16 Zealot
18 Zealot
18 Pylon
18 Continue Zealot production until the attack is over.

Your Probe should get to the proxy location in time to build a Pylon as soon as 100 minerals have been accumulated. Because the rush distance is different for different maps, you may wish to test the timing at which you need to send a Probe for any map you're planning to use this strategy on.
You should choose a proxy location that isn't along the common scouting path your opponent is likely to take.
You also have to decide whether you want to build the Gateways inside your opponent's base or in a more remote location. Building them unnoticed in your opponent's base is obviously stronger but it's also a lot more likely to be scouted in time. A more remote location is safer but it also makes it harder to succeed due to the larger distances.</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Photon Cannon rush</buildname>
    <race>protoss</race>
    <buildinstructions>
The main goal of the Photon Cannon rush is to quickly place Photon Cannons in range of the opponent's production buildings or mineral lines. This forces them to either initiate a potentially costly counter-attack or accept the loss of key structures or workers.
        
9 Pylon
13 Forge
14 Pylon (optional)
14 Additional Pylons and/or Photon Cannons


A typical adaptation of the cannon rush is to use Pylons to completely wall off cannons behind the mineral line.[1] The idea is to make it impossible for the defending player to attack the cannons with workers or melee units, while being able to completely deny mining in the main. The strategy works best on maps that have locations in the main that can be completely walled off using 3 or fewer Pylons.

</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>1/1/1 All In 10 Minute Timing</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>2 versions
        
        10 - Supply Depot (1)
12 - Barracks (1)
13 - Refinery (1)
15 - Orbital Command Upgrade
15 - Marine (1)
16 - Barracks (2)
16 - Reactor (1) on Barracks (1)
17 - Supply Depot (2)
19 - Marines
21 - Supply Depot (3)
21 - Tech Lab on Barracks (2)
22 - Marines
25 - Concussive Shells
25 - Marauders (to 2)
28 - Supply Depot (4)
33 - Factory
36 - Refinery (2)
36 - Reactor (2) on Barracks (2)
41 - Starport
41 - @22 SCVs > Cut SCV production
45 - Supply Depot (5)
47 - Tech Lab (2) on Factory
52 - Supply Depot (6)
52 - Banshee and Siege Tank production
60ish - @100% Banshee (1) > Cut Marine Production until Vespene Gas spent to 0
66 - Siege Tech



or....

10 - Supply Depot (1)
12 - Barracks
13 - Refinery
15 - Orbital Command upgrade
15 - Marine (to 4)
16 - Supply Depot (2)
18 - Factory
19 - Refinery (2)
@100% Marine (4) - Barracks (1) builds Reactor, make Marines with spare minerals, but spend gas first
22 - Starport
Factory builds Tech Lab (1) > Switch to Starport @100% > Tech Lab (2)
25 - Banshees, harass Sentry numbers at completion
Optional - Cloak upgrade
Start Siege Tanks (to 2 or 3) + Siege Mode
50 Barracks (2) (3)
Start continual Marine and Banshee production
With Siege Tank (3) or high Stalker numbers
bring half SCV on mineral line
Switch Starport to Reactor (1) > Medivacs (1) (2)
Switch Barracks (2) (3) to Tech Labs (1) (2) > Marauders

</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>Marine/Hellion/Banshee</buildname>
    <race>terran</race>
    <buildinstructions>10 - Supply Depot (1)
12 - Refinery (1)
13 - Barracks
16 - Factory
16 - Orbital Command Upgrade
16 - Marine (1)
17 - Supply Depot (2)
17 - Reactor on Barracks
18 - Refinery (2), if going for Cloaking Field Upgrade
19 - Hellion (1)
22 - Starport
22 - Supply Depot (3)
23 - Tech Lab on Factory > Switch to Starport, if Banshees
23 - Marines or Hellions, See first Note
26 or 28 - Banshees or Medivac (1)</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  <buildorder>
    <buildname>intial build 33</buildname>
    <race>other</race>
    <buildinstructions>buildinstructions blah blah blah</buildinstructions>
  </buildorder>
  
  
  
</buildorderfile>
